Finding Aid for Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company records, 1871-1920
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company records
1871-1920
Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company.
86346 Bb.2; BB.2
Corporate records of C.J.L. Meyer of Fond du Lac, Wisconsin and Hermansville, Michigan, manufacturer of doors, lumber for sashes, hardwood flooring, and related products; records of the William Mueller Company of Escanaba and LaBranche, Michigan, a firm taken over by Wisconsin Land and Lumber in 1909. Financial journals, ledgers, inventories, payroll ledgers; letterbooks of C.J.L. Meyer, Edwin P. Radford, company superintendent, and of other company officials; office correspondence files; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
42 linear feet
65 oversize volumes
71 microfilms
The record group was donated by G. Harold Earle (donor no. 2290 ) in 1948. In 2007, the IXL Museum, in an exchange with the Bentley Library, donated 18 microfilm rolls of photographs and company records, and 4 computer disks of digitized photographs.
The record group is open to research. There are restrictions on the copying of the images from the compact discs in box 50 for commercial purposes; researchers should contact the IXL Museum in Hermansville, Michigan to obtain these copies.
The Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company of Hermansville, Michigan was originally founded as a subsidiary firm of Charles J. L. Meyer, a successful Chicago and Wisconsin businessman. Meyer, following the Chicago fire of 1871, made a fortune by expanding his door and sash manufacturing plant located in Fond du Lac, Wisconsin. As one of the few such facilities in the upper Great Lakes region, Meyer profited handsomely from the rebuilding of Chicago.
By the mid-1870s, lumber supplies in the Lake Winnebago region of Wisconsin were being depleted; and Meyer, to insure himself a supply of wood, purchased the Menominee County, Michigan land holdings of the Hamilton Merriman Company. In 1879, Meyer relocated the sawmill he owned in Fond du Lac to his Michigan property. The site of the mill became Hermansville (named after his son). Mill No. 1, as the facility was called, was a softwood mill, preparing pine for shipment to Fond du Lac. His Michigan property, however, also had significant stands of hardwood trees on it, and so, in 1882, Meyer began to operate kilns in Hermansville to convert the hardwood into charcoal.
The production of charcoal never proved profitable, however, and Meyer continued to search for a way to use his hardwood lumber. After much study, he concluded that a market did exist for hardwood floors. The problem was that there was no satisfactory machinery to mill hardwood into flooring. After years of experimentation, he finally perfected his "Meyer matchers," milling machines which made possible the mass production of acceptable hardwood flooring. Meyer had begun construction of a hardwood flooring facility in Hermansville in 1885. That factory was completed in 1888 and the first regularly scheduled commercial production in the plant began in 1889.
While Meyer had identified a potential market and developed the necessary machinery to produce an acceptable product, he was unable to deal successfully with his rapidly failing financial situation. In the fall of 1889 his five companies fell into the hands of creditors, who appointed Henry A. Jewell to oversee operations. To pay the creditors, Jewell sold all of Meyer's asset except for Wisconsin Land and Lumber in Hermansville. When the firm emerged from receivership in 1892, C.J.L. Meyer was titular head of the Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company, but actual control of the company had slipped into the hands of his son-in-law, Dr. George Washington Earle.
Earle, who had received his medical degree from Buffalo Medical College and practiced in New York State, had come to Hermansville in 1889 for reasons of health. He had already invested in Wisconsin Land and Lumber and throughout the period of receivership and the next few years, he found himself pouring more and more money into the firm, in an effort to save his initial investment. As his financial investment grew, so too did his control of day-to-day operations.
For a time the firm's finances remained precarious, suffering a serious setback when Mill No. 1 burned in 1891 and had to be rebuilt. In the end, however, Meyer's estimate that there was a steady trade in hardwood flooring proved accurate, and the firm flourished. In 1901 the pine mill (No. 1) was rebuilt. In 1910 it burned and was replaced. In 1911 the hardwood mill (No. 2) was rebuilt of concrete. In 1909 the firm was assured an adequate supply of timber when it bought the assets of the bankrupt William Mueller Company at a sheriff's sale. Most significant in this sale were large stands of timber near Blaney, Michigan.
G. W. Earle died in 1923. His sons, G. Harold and Stewart, took over the family business. During the 1930s, the firm entered a period of slow decline. In 1939 the No. 2 mill closed, followed by the No. 1 mill and the flooring factory in 1943.
This record group which came from the Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company in Hermansville, Michigan is in fact an accumulation of records from three distinct business enterprises. First, there are records of C.J.L. Meyer business enterprises in Chicago and Fond du Lac, Wisconsin. Next are records maintained in Hermansville with the establishment of the Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company in the 1870s. A third, smaller portion of the records are from the William Mueller Company, which WLL purchased in 1909.
When originally received in 1948, the records consisted of nearly 500 volumes of business journals and ledgers, time books, and letterpress books. During 1979-1981, the library began a program of microfilming to reduce the size of the record group. With the permission of the company, records that had been microfilmed were discarded. Also discarded were records duplicative in content of the records on microfilm. Other records were retained in the original without filming. The record group then consisted of 53 reels of microfilm representing approximately 112 volumes of business records, 65 oversized volumes, and 42 linear feet of boxed records (volumes, letterpress books, and correspondence files). In 2006, the library received additional microfilm (18 rolls) and computer disks containing scanned images of the photographs in the possession of the IXL Museum, which is the repository for the records of the company not received with the first accession. These records, which were retained, include personal correspondence of C.J.L. Meyer, some records of Meyer prior to the establishment of WLL, and records then considered current or of continuing value to the operation of the company.
The record group has been arranged as much as possible into series, but the researcher should note that identification of individuals volumes or files was not as certain as one would like. Thus, for example, there are various ledgers and journals, some with overlapping dates, but it was not always clear where these records were created or what function or division within the firm they documented. The fact that the company retained some of the earlier records accounts in part for what appear to be broken series. Further complicating the structure of the following finding aid is the interspersing of microfilmed materials and oversize volumes. Similar kinds of records (such as time books), for example, are thus found both in original and on microfilm.
As much as possible, like kinds of records have been kept to together (letterpress books, etc.). These are followed by records known to be created by a specific organization or maintained in a specific locale (e.g. Fond du Lac). The series in the record group are: Letterpress books (mainly business correspondence); Letterpress books (mainly business correspondence); Inventories, order books, etc.; C. J. L. Meyer Business Records; Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company; William Mueller Company; Photographs; and IXL Museum additions.
In 2007, the IXL Museum of Hermansville, Michigan, successor to the company and custodian of additional records of the Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company, entered into agreement with the Bentley Library to exchange microfilm of selected portions of the records housed in the other's repository. In addition, the two repositories agreed that the Bentley Library would place on indefinite loan to the IXL Museum the originals of WLL photographs in its possession, and that the IXL Museum would donated to the Bentley Library digital copies of all of the many hundreds of photographs in its collection.
Summary Contents List
Letterpress books (mainly business correspondence) Superintendent Edwin P. Radford (originals) -- Boxes 1-6 General Land Office (originals) -- Boxes 6-9 Corporate Staff and Miscellaneous (originals) -- Boxes 9-12, 18-20, 38-39
Correspondence files (business) (originals) -- Boxes 21-30
Inventories, order books, etc. (originals) -- Boxes 13-14, 31-37, 40-45
C.J. L. Meyer Business Records (originals) Fond du Lac milling and manufacturing enterprises Various financial records (originals) -- outsize volumes Order books, vol. 1-5 (microfilm) -- Reels 17-20 Miscellaneous financial records (originals) -- outsize volumes General Journal (microfilm) -- Reels 1-5 Sawmill Journals (microfilm) -- Reels 5-10 Sawmill Payroll Ledgers -- (microfilm) -- Reels 10-13 General Payroll Ledgers and misc. (microfilm) -- Reels 13-17
Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company Journals (microfilm) -- Reels 20-25 General Ledgers (microfilm) -- Reels 25-33 Payroll Ledgers (microfilm) -- 33-51 Camp Payroll Books (microfilm) Reel 51 Payroll records and Miscellaneous (microfilm) -- Reels 51-52 Miscellaneous account and Inventory books (originals) -- outsize vols.
William Mueller Company (originals) -- outsize volumes
Photographs Album (microfilm) -- Reel 53 Photocopies of images -- Box 49 Digital Images (of item s on loan to IXL Museum) -- Box 50 Photo albums (microfilm) -- Box 50 reel 1
Miscellaneous records received in 2007 (microfilm) Box 50 Reels 2-18
Subjects:
Business records.; Escanaba (Mich.); Fond du Lac (Wis.); Hermansville (Mich.); Lumbering--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; Logging--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; William Mueller Company.; Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bicycles and tricycles.; Churches--Michigan--Hermansville.; Dams--Michigan--Hermansville.; Educational buildings--Michigan--Hermansville.; Hermansville (Mich.); Hotels and taverns--Michigan--Hermansville.; Laborers.; Lumber industry--Michigan--Hermansville.; Menominee River Boom Company.; Methodist churches--Michigan--Hermansville.; Mills--Michigan--Hermansville.; Minneapolis, St. Paul & Sault Ste. Marie Railway Company.; Railroad construction and maintenance.; Railroad stations--Michigan--Hermansville.; Railroads--Michigan.; Schools--Michigan--Hermansville.; Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company.
Contributors:
Meyer, C. J. L.; Radford, Edwin P.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Letterpress books, 1872-1922
  (mainly business correspondence)
  - Superintendent Edwin P. Radford, 1883-1919
    - January 1883-March 1899 (Box 1)
    - March 1899-June 1903 (Box 2)
    - June 1903-April 1907 (Box 3)
    - April 1907-May 1910 (Box 4)
    - May 1910-July 1914 (Box 5)
    - July 1914-July 1919 (Box 6)
  - General and Office, 1897-1922
    - October 1897-November 1900 (Box 6)
    - November 1900-June 1910 (Box 7)
    - June 1910-December 1918 (Box 8)
    - December 1918-December 1922 (Box 9)
      (missing volume for parts of 1919-1920)
  - Carl A. Ebert and Fred J. Lang, January 1883-November 1899
    - January 1883-July 1887 (Box 9)
    - July 1887-November 1889 (Box 10)
  - Henry A. Jewell, assignee
    - December 1889-June 1891 (Box 10)
  - Fond du Lac Sash and Door Co.
    - May 1884-November 1889 (Box 11)
  - Fond du Lac Furniture Co.
    - May 1884-1886, 1888-1889 (Box 12)
  - Wisconsin Window Blind Company
    - February 1878-May 1890 (Box 12)
  - George H. Francis, assistant secretary (Box 18)
    - May-December 1888 (Box 18)
    - August 1889-December 1890 (Box 18)
  - J.W. Stow, Hermansville
    - May 1882-March 1883 (Box 18)
  - C.J. Meyer, West Avenue Lumber Yard
    - January 1879-May 1883 (Box 18)
  - W.A. Griffith
    - 1887-1889, 3 volumes (Box 18)
  - C. J .L. Meyer, February 1881-1889 (Box 19)
    - February-December 1881 (Box 19)
    - September 1881-May 1882 (Box 19)
    - September 1881-August 1882 (Box 19)
    - August 1882-December 1882 (Box 19)
    - February 1884-January 1885 (Box 19)
    - December 1885-December 1886 (Box 19)
    - December 1886-June 1889 (Box 20)
  - Oscar C. Egen
    - December 1877-May 1880 (Box 20)
  - Hannibal Woodworth, assistant secretary
    - January 1883-June 1884 (Box 20)
  - [Not labeled]
    - August 1873-July 1881 (Box 20)
  - Carl A. Ebert
    - April 1881-March 1882 (Box 20)
  - Elisha J. Filghum, plant superintendent
    - March 1913-August 1914 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous letterbooks (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous letterbooks, including some of William Mueller Company, Escanaba, Michigan (Box 39)
  - Scale books (Box 39)
- Correspondence files (business), 1887-1915
  - 1887-1898 (Box 21)
  - November 1898-April 1900 (Box 22)
  - 1900-November 1906 (Box 23)
  - November 1906-March 1908 (Box 24)
  - April 1908-December 1909 (Box 25)
  - 1910-1911 (Box 26)
  - 1911-1912 (Box 27)
  - July-November 1912 (Box 28)
  - February-July 1913 (Box 28)
  - July 1913-September 1914 (Box 29)
  - 1914-1915 (Box 30)
- Inventories, order books, etc.
  - Annual statements, inventories, etc. (Box 31)
  - Order Books (Box 13)
  - Order Books (Box 14)
    (continued)
  - Inventory books (Box 32)
  - Inventory books (Box 33)
  - Inventory books (Box 34)
  - Inventory books (Box 35)
  - Inventory books (Box 36)
  - Inventory books (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous volumes (unlisted) (Box 45)
- C. J. L. Meyer Business Records, 1871-1889
  - Fond du Lac milling and manufacturing enterprises
    (see also microfilm reels 17-20)
    - Petty cash book, 1882-1883 (Volume 16)
    - General cash book, 1874-1876 (Volume 18)
    - General cash book, 1879-1880 (Volume 21)
    - General cash book, 1880-1881 (Volume 20)
    - General cash book, 1882-1884 (Volume 19)
    - General cash book, 1885-1886 (Volume 17)
    - Cash book, 1871-1873 (Volume 41)
    - Cash book, June 1881-September 1882 (Volume 39)
    - Cash book, September 1882-January 1883 (Volume 38)
    - Day book, July 1879-December 1880 (Volume 46)
    - Day book, January 1880-December 1881 (Volume 49)
    - Day book, December 1880-September 1882 (Volume 45)
    - Day book, 1882-1884 (Volume 32)
    - Day book, 1883-1884 (Volume 30)
    - Journal, October 1884-December 1885 (Volume 29)
    - Journal, July 1884-December 1885 (Volume 43)
    - Sales Account, 1880 (Volume 65)
    - Orders from Chicago, 1882-1885 (Volume 23)
    - Orders from Chicago, 1885-1889 (Volume 26)
    - Main Street Yard journal, 1873-1877 (Volume 28)
    - Main Street Yard ledger, May 1873-December 1875 (Volume 35)
    - Saw Mill journal, June 1886-August 1888 (Volume 34)
    - Sash and Door Company
      - Ledger, April 1883-December 1885 (Volume 31)
      - Journal, April 1883-November 1887 (Volume 36)
      - Journal, October 1887-August 1889 (Volume 33)
  - Miscellaneous financial records
    - Chicago House cash book, 1877-1878 (Volume 22)
    - Ledger, 1879-April 1880 (Volume 42)
    - Ledger, June 1882-January 1883 (Volume 24)
    - Ledger, October 1882-December 1882 (Volume 37)
    - Warehouse Accounts, Doors, Sash and Blinds, circa 1871-1889 (Volume 25)
    - Journal #2, 1881-1882 (Volume 44)
    - Journal #3, 1882-1883 (Volume 27)
    - Journal, March 1887-December 1888 (Volume 51)
  - General Journal
    (microfilm negative only of some reels; no access until positive copy is made)
    - 1871-1873 (Box 46, Reel 1)
      (negative only)
    - 1873-1874 (Box 46, Reel 1)
    - 1874-1876 (Box 46, Reel 2)
    - 1876-1877 (Box 46, Reel 2)
    - 1877-1879 (Box 46, Reel 2)
    - (cont.), 1877-1879 (Box 46, Reel 3)
    - 1879-1880 (Box 46, Reel 3)
    - 1880-1882 (Box 46, Reel 3)
    - (cont.), 1880-1882 (Box 46, Reel 4)
    - 1882-1884 (Box 46, Reel 4)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 46, Reel 4)
    - (cont.), 1884-1886 (Box 46, Reel 5)
    - 1886-1887 (Box 46, Reel 5)
  - Sawmill Journals-General Ledgers
    - 1871-1874 (Box 46, Reel 5)
    - 1876-1879 (Box 46, Reel 6)
    - (cont.), 1876-1879 (Box 46, Reel 7)
    - 1879-1881 (Box 46, Reel 7)
    - (cont.), 1879-1881 (Box 46, Reel 8)
    - 1881-1883 (Box 46, Reel 8)
    - 1883-1885 (Box 46, Reel 8)
    - (cont.), 1883-1885 (Box 46, Reel 9)
    - 1885-1887 (Box 46, Reel 9)
    - (cont.), 1885-1887 (Box 46, Reel 10)
  - Sawmill payroll ledgers
    - 1873-1876 (Box 46, Reel 10)
    - 1876-1880 (Box 46, Reel 10)
    - (cont.), 1876-1880 (Box 46, Reel 11)
    - 1882-1884 (Box 46, Reel 11)
    - (cont.), 1882-1884 (Box 46, Reel 12)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 46, Reel 12)
    - 1888-1890 (Box 46, Reel 12)
    - (cont.), 1888-1890 (Box 46, Reel 13)
  - General payroll ledger
    - 1874-1877 (Box 46, Reel 13)
    - 1878-1882 (Box 46, Reel 13)
    - (cont.), 1878-1882 (Box 46, Reel 14)
    - 1882-1887 (Box 46, Reel 14)
    - 1887-1889 (Box 46, Reel 14)
    - 1873-1875 (Box 46, Reel 14)
    - (cont.), 1873-1875 (Box 46, Reel 15)
    - 1877-1882 (Box 46, Reel 15)
    - 1883-1888 (Box 46, Reel 15)
    - (cont.), 1883-1888 (Box 46, Reel 16)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 46, Reel 16)
    - 1880 (Box 46, Reel 16)
  - Real estate ledger
    - circa 1883-1890 (Box 46, Reel 16)
  - Shipping book
    - 1871 (Box 46, Reel 16)
    - (cont.), 1871 (Box 46, Reel 17)
  - General Order Book (no. 4)
    - 1880-1881 (Box 46, Reel 17)
  - Fond du Lac Sash and Door Company
    - Order books No. 1, 1883-1884 (Box 46, Reel 17)
    - Order books No. 1 (cont.), 1883-1884 (Box 46, Reel 18)
    - Order books No. 2, 1884-1885 (Box 46, Reel 18)
    - Order books No. 3, 1885-1887 (Box 46, Reel 18)
    - Order books No. 3 (cont.), 1885-1887 (Box 46, Reel 19)
    - Order books No. 4, 1887-1889 (Box 46, Reel 19)
    - Order books No. 5, June-December 1889 (Box 46, Reel 19)
    - Order books No. 5 (cont.), June-December 1889 (Box 46, Reel 20)
- Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company, 1883-1893
  - Journals
    - January-October 1883 (Box 46, Reel 20)
    - October 1883-December 1884 (Box 46, Reel 20)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 46, Reel 21)
    - 1886-1888 (Box 46, Reel 21)
    - (cont.), 1886-1888 (Box 46, Reel 22)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 46, Reel 22)
    - September-December 1889 (Box 46, Reel 22)
    - 1889-1890 (Box 46, Reel 22)
    - (cont.), 1889-1890 (Box 46, Reel 23)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 46, Reel 23)
    - 1892-1893 (Box 46, Reel 23)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 46, Reel 24)
    - 1892-1893 (Box 46, Reel 24)
    - (cont.), 1892-1893 (Box 46, Reel 25)
  - General ledgers
    - 1883-1884 (Box 46, Reel 25)
    - 1885-1888 (Box 46, Reel 25)
    - (cont.), 1885-1888 (Box 47, Reel 26)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 47, Reel 26)
    - 1889-1890 (Box 47, Reel 26)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 47, Reel 26)
    - (cont.), 1890-1891 (Box 47, Reel 27)
    - 1892-1893 (Box 47, Reel 27)
    - (cont.), 1892-1893 (Box 47, Reel 28)
    - 1894-1896 (Box 47, Reel 28)
    - 1897-1899 (Box 47, Reel 28)
    - 1881-1882 (Box 47, Reel 28)
    - (cont.), 1881-1882 (Box 47, Reel 29)
    - 1883-1884 (Box 47, Reel 29)
    - (cont.), 1883-1884 (Box 47, Reel 30)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 47, Reel 30)
    - 1887-1888 (Box 47, Reel 30)
    - (cont.), 1887-1888 (Box 47, Reel 31)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 47, Reel 31)
    - 1889-1891 (Box 47, Reel 31)
    - (cont.), 1889-1891 (Box 47, Reel 32)
    - 1892-1896 (Box 47, Reel 32)
    - (cont.), 1892-1896 (Box 47, Reel 33)
  - Payroll ledgers
    - (C. J. L. Meyer payroll ledger), 1883 (Box 47, Reel 33)
    - (C. J. L. Meyer payroll ledger), 1884 (Box 47, Reel 33)
    - 1885-1886 (Box 47, Reel 33)
    - (cont.), 1885-1886 (Box 47, Reel 34)
    - 1886-1887 (Box 47, Reel 34)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 47, Reel 34)
    - (cont.), 1888-1889 (Box 47, Reel 35)
    - April-October 1889 (Box 47, Reel 35)
    - 1889-1890 (Box 47, Reel 35)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 47, Reel 35)
    - (cont.), 1890-1891 (Box 47, Reel 36)
    - 1891-1892 (Box 47, Reel 36)
    - 1892-1893 (Box 47, Reel 36)
    - 1894-1895 (Box 47, Reel 36)
    - (cont.), 1894-1895 (Box 47, Reel 37)
    - 1895-1896 (Box 47, Reel 37)
    - 1896-1897 (Box 47, Reel 37)
    - (cont.), 1896-1897 (Box 47, Reel 38)
    - 1897-1898 (Box 47, Reel 38)
    - 1898-1899 (Box 47, Reel 38)
    - (cont.), 1898-1899 (Box 47, Reel 39)
    - 1899-1900 (Box 47, Reel 39)
    - 1900-1901 (Box 47, Reel 39)
    - (cont.), 1900-1901 (Box 47, Reel 40)
    - (cont.), 1900-1901 (Box 47, Reel 41)
    - 1901-1902 (Box 47, Reel 41)
    - (cont.), 1901-1902 (Box 47, Reel 42)
    - 1902-1903 (Box 47, Reel 42)
    - 1903-1904 (Box 47, Reel 42)
    - (cont.), 1903-1904 (Box 47, Reel 43)
    - 1904-1905 (Box 47, Reel 43)
    - 1905-1906 (Box 47, Reel 43)
    - (cont.), 1905-1906 (Box 47, Reel 44)
    - 1906-1907 (Box 47, Reel 44)
    - 1907-1908 (Box 47, Reel 44)
    - (cont.), 1907-1908 (Box 47, Reel 45)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 47, Reel 45)
    - 1909-1910 (Box 47, Reel 45)
    - (cont.), 1909-1910 (Box 47, Reel 46)
    - 1910-1911 (Box 47, Reel 46)
    - 1911-1912 (Box 47, Reel 46)
    - 1912-1913 (Box 47, Reel 46)
    - (cont.), 1912-1913 (Box 47, Reel 47)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 47, Reel 47)
    - 1914-1915 (Box 47, Reel 47)
    - (cont.), 1914-1915 (Box 47, Reel 48)
    - 1915-1916 (Box 47, Reel 48)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 47, Reel 48)
    - 1917-1918 (Box 47, Reel 48)
    - (cont.), 1917-1918 (Box 47, Reel 49)
    - 1918-1919 (Box 47, Reel 49)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 47, Reel 49)
    - (cont.), 1919-1920 (Box 47, Reel 50)
  - Camp Time Books
    - 1891-1896 (Box 47, Reel 50)
    - 1896-1900 (Box 47, Reel 50)
    - 1900-1907 (Box 47, Reel 50)
    - 1900-1907 (Box 47, Reel 51)
  - Camp Payroll Books
    - 1907-1914 (Box 47, Reel 51)
    - 1913-1915 (Box 47, Reel 51)
  - Payroll Records (Blaney)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 47, Reel 51)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 47, Reel 51)
    - (cont.), 1919-1920 (Box 47, Reel 52)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 47, Reel 52)
  - Camp Time Book
    - 1914-1921 (Box 47, Reel 52)
  - Labor Classification
    - 1890-1899 (Box 47, Reel 52)
  - Time Book and Payroll
    - March-August 1904 (Box 47, Reel 52)
  - Camp Records
    - 1905-1906 (Box 47, Reel 52)
  - Master negative of microfilm (Box 48)
    (staff use only; positive use copy of most reels in boxes 46-47)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Ledger, January 1886-June 1887 (Volume 40)
    - Sales Reports, August-December 1883 (Volume 47)
    - Account book of company camps season, 1913-1914 (Volume 48)
    - Sales, 1881 (Volume 50)
    - Journal (Fond du Lac Office), January 1883-February 1885 (Volume 52)
    - Inventory books
      - January 1888, July 1889 (Volume 62)
      - 1894 (Volume 63)
      - 1898 (Volume 64)
      - 1900 (Volume 57)
      - 1901 (Volume 58)
      - 1907 (Volume 60)
      - 1910 (Volume 59)
      - 1914 (Volume 61)
      - 1916 (Volume 56)
      - 1918 (Volume 54)
      - 1919 (Volume 53)
      - 1920 (Volume 55)
- William Mueller Company, 1899-1921
  - Escanaba
    - Ledger, November 1899-August 1902 (Volume 1)
    - Ledger, 1902-1906 (Volume 2)
    - Journal, November 1899-October 1902 (Volume 3)
    - Journal, November 1902-March 1906 (Volume 4)
    - Poles Delivered and Direct Shipments, 1900-1905 (Volume 5)
    - Poles Received, 1900-1906 (Volume 6)
  - LaBranche
    - Journal Cash Book, 1906-1911 (Volume 7)
    - Journal, April 1904-December 1905 (Volume 8)
    - Cash Book, April 1904-July 1906 (Volume 9)